hello and welcome back to another
episode of hermitcraft today behind me i
have myself a brand new
pesky bird this one is actually for a
brand new delivery to rendog who has
requested a bunch of gunpowder which i
have been collecting up
and now it's time to take it over to him
i've loaded up all of these shulker
boxes and we are ready to go
and speaking of pesky birds has iskal
gone and bought the original one or is
he procrastinating no there is there's
the original pesky bird and and it
doesn't look like he's paid for this yet
i know he's gonna buy it because look
how many leaves he's gonna need this is
literally a deal he cannot turn down so
let's uh let's encourage him with a bit
more diuret on this
if he doesn't if he doesn't hurry up
this whole thing will end up completely
covered yeah this guy if you don't hurry
up you're going to be buying a lot more
diorite or pesky bird poop as it now
should be known right so let's go and
take the other pesky bird over to rendog
whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa use you back
off you get away from that pesky bird i
don't i don't know if ocelots go for
birds but i know that cats go for
chickens and stuff
you yeah you walk away looks like i got
everything
time to take you over now actually i
don't know where ren's base actually is
but we should drop it off oh hello we
should drop it off where his tree farm
is
this is so cute
how they follow you paris one of the
cutest things i swear and this i believe
is part of ren's stuff that's his i've
been here several times because i've had
to steal his doors
actually while we're here we might as
well pick a couple up
yeah
delivery delivery and doors and he's got
his whole like western themed town here
as well
see he hasn't even bothered replacing
the doors i took here well his bed is
here this looks like a really good place
for the pesky bird drop all right you
stay there little one and now let's go
and make this thing
i'm pretty sure this is his tree farm by
the looks of things
and i'm guessing this is also where he
needs all the tnt like he's just got to
i think he's got to fuel this machine
and that's what all this is for so we're
gonna give him the deal of the century
pesky bird they're actually quite quick
to build now that i know what i'm doing
with it all okay this is okay this is
just about finished i made it maybe a
little bit
wonky but that's not a big deal because
these things are always temporary so we
just need to get the pesky bird up there
there we go
come on no no
you're up here
ah you stupid bird sure you'll you'll
stand on top of the lantern the smallest
thing but you wouldn't land on the nice
platform that i made for you yay
no no he's there
come on come on
off you get right let's push you push
you into the middle
no
pesky bad
no no
okay this one's being a lot more trouble
than the other there we go there we go
that's the ticket boom yes success pesky
bird is currently carrying
the delivery now with every pesky bird
delivery
there is always always a catch with
iskall we're forcing him to buy diorite
which is his absolute most hated block
in the whole of minecraft and it's gonna
actually hurt his soul to purchase it
with ren
i think we should do something a little
more subtle
and something that will benefit us later
on
so what we're gonna drop in here
is a
ren
ren o's green a favor this is an iou
from ren to me that he's going to buy
himself
as part of the deal so we'll hide it in
the middle of the chest right at the
bottom of the pile and then we'll
surround it with all the other chests
and fill these up with gunpowder
that way
he won't even know that he's bought his
own iou right let's take all of these
upstairs and start cashing them in okay
everything is set up all of these have
gun powder in them and of course we've
got the ticket in here as well pesky
bird is all set up just time to leave
ren some signs
and of course work out how much we're
gonna charge for all this okay so there
it there is officially 350
stacks 350 stacks of gunpowder
now
it actually takes five stacks to make
one stack so i think that's about fair
to ask for 70 diamonds that is a
phenomenal deal that means he's getting
five stacks of gunpowder for just one
diamond absolutely insane in fact that
might be too insane now for context one
stack of gunpowder costs one diamond in
the shopping district so he's getting
over four stacks for one diamond really
really good deal hello ren the pesky
bird is here to give you an offer you
can't refuse
today pb is offering the entire barge
minus the pb for just 70 diamonds i
never really gave instructions on how to
pay for this
there we go leave the diamonds in my
base with a note to accept all right
that is pesky bird offer number two
between this and iscal sale we could be
making some serious diamonds but
honestly this is every single piece of
gunpowder that mine and scars machine
has produced and don't worry i will be
sharing the profits of this pesky bird
delivery with scar okay now that we're
done here why don't we head over to the
shopping district where's ren's portal
that's here and why don't we spend some
diamonds because i think these are going
to give us a pretty good profit why
don't we go and spend something
here we are at isgals treasure island i
really want to give this a go i would
really like to get the jackpot according
to these guys impulse and tango
it's still up for grabs so i don't
actually have that many diamonds but i
feel like we could uh yeah we could do
maybe three blocks of this
all right so here we go one
two three
and without looking inside
let's go
one
two
three check it out let's go for this one
first
oh you know i got my money back free
free shulker box this one
sand yeah okay
uh duds
duds
we're we're all just spinning the wheel
we're just taking it in turn to buy all
of these up go on tango what did you get
oh still not there okay right my turn
roll the dice
all right i'm gonna go for
take a look
blaze rods
oh man
got some duds in here
oh well actually i need i needed these
shulker boxes so not too bad but
no i'm i'm out i'm out i'm
i'm out that was
diamond's gone
if if the if the jackpot really is still
in there people have got a pretty good
chance
i can reclaim some of this money by
putting the gravel and sand that i just
won back into the shop
there we go we may need to take our
investment money back because i just
wasted it all on on the treasure island
and i heard there is a new shop on the
block by mumbo jumbo i took a look at
his video and it turns out he's selling
him bits of him including
his famous mustache
so let's have a look i've completely run
out of diamonds and desperate times lead
to desperate measures so i've built this
store
by mumbo's bits
oh my goodness buy mumbo's mustache buy
my suit buy my hair
well there's only one thing we're
interested in and that's by my
[Music]
no
it's gone
the stash is gone and the suit okay the
suit's still here and the hair's still
here
oh my goodness scar why are you blue
what is wrong with you oh yeah i could
tell i can see that i i can see that
oops sorry let me shout okay
i have an idea i can't get the mustache
because someone's already bought it but
what i am going to do is buy his hair
i will buy his hair
and i have i have a one mumbo hair token
and i have a plan i know exactly what to
do with this so we'll pop that in there
that is 16 diamonds well spent time to
message mumbo and let him know this
should be absolutely magnificent we
spent a lot of diamonds today on the
island and then we just bought a piece
of mumbo what could be better now that
i've got this the mumbo hair token
i have the best idea
mumbo's not quite online yet so we'll
just wait for him but as soon as he is
we are going to we're gonna we're gonna
cash this thing in let's go and check if
iskal has decided to buy the pesky oh
well well well
look who decided to pay up
well i guess we'll be back when he's
done with that then
ah and speak of the devil and he shall
come mumbo jumbo has just logged on i've
got my hair token i'm ready to cash this
in
let's go and see if we can find
the mustache man himself and give him a
little haircut his new base is here oh
wow he's doing some work on it where is
he
hello
look at all my messages
oh he's like he's right there
hello uh
i would like
to cash this in
boom
yes siri he's still got his mustache on
but what's this okay i'm gonna i'm gonna
give him a call
dude so you bought my hair all right
my outfit is already looking rocking as
you can see
[Laughter]
what is going on there with some really
long trousers yeah so so iskall is girl
noticed that i was wearing my my purple
belt quite high up my chest all right so
he thought
he would work off of this
and give me some some old man jeans
basically so
i don't know why he decided to do the
short sleeves oh he's rolled up the
sleeves as well
it makes you look so buff
it's a it's a strange look for me i mean
i
honestly i did say like it's kind of a
little bit flattering it's not something
that i think is going to stick around
but i'm not mad at it
i i can't help but notice that your
mustache is still on your face has yes
it's been sold because that's what i
went for and i did like a darth vader no
i was like no
but it's still on your face
yeah yeah so i think uh tango's
purchased it and i think he's working on
the on the redesign
uh right as we speak which
is yeah that's uh i'm i'm kind of i'm
kind of scared for that one i'm kind of
scared to see what direction that goes
in i could end up being like a jumbled
mess of a human being but at least i
made one and a half stacks of diamonds
that's all that matters yeah easy
diamonds easy diamonds
okay so i'm gonna send you the skin for
your hair transplant
all right and uh yeah this is gonna be
good you ready all right i'll go i'll go
down here right and i'll do a reveal
i'll pop up through the uh through the
ladders how does that sound sounds great
okay my hair is now on
oh gosh oh gosh i forgot i forgot that
you get my mustache i forget that
there's a hot swap involved
no well i didn't buy your mustache but i
really really wanted your mustache if
you press press f5 really quick oh no
what have you done what have you done
hang on hang on have you taken a patch
of my hair and put it on your face and i
have a patch of your hair and it's on
the no i've got a rear mustache
[Laughter]
dude
hang on have you cut it from the back of
your head or did you no no no no no i've
just i've literally just like got you've
got a board spot i've just cut out i've
just cut out a patch of your hair and
i've put on my face
couldn't get your mustache so this is
the next best thing
so
that
oh man so you've shaved off a patch of
the back of my head and you've you've
you've glue sticked you've pre-sticked
it onto your face is what you've done
yeah this is horrendous this is the next
best thing
[Laughter]
oh my goodness well this is not now this
is non-dark i look i look a mess
i seriously look at me
just i should have cut out some eyes on
the back as well oh my goodness i mean
you know that that can
maybe we can add some expressions
maybe this can be like my normal face
and an angry face i can just go back and
forth my goodness i can't believe i've
got a bald spot now i got i got a cheap
i got a cheap knockoff version of your
mustache
well i mean it it forever suits you dude
i mean the uh
the connection of the eyes to mustache
that you always have going on whenever
you're rocking
i feel really manly
go chop some trees i can see you holding
that axe you're
you're set and ready
well i'm gonna keep how long do i get to
keep this for honestly no idea i i don't
i didn't think that far ahead so
i mean forever bye
this is mine no rules keeping this being
macho man forever
i've got to i've got to spend the rest
of the season like this and i have to
look at you like that as well
goodness me
i cannot believe we got mumbos well not
exactly mustache but
it basically is right but now that i'm
in possession of the manliest redstone
mustache that there is
i think i really need while i still own
it to get redstone done like as soon as
possible i've got two issues one i don't
know how long i can keep this mustache
for and two the chest monster situation
is growing out of hand if you remember
the start of the season
i made this to keep everything organized
and it worked for about two days now i
need a system an item sorter where i can
just dump the shulker boxes and not have
to look at it again and it just sorts
itself
i need a proper item sorter because this
is is getting really out of hand and
it's only going to grow and grow and
grow
this leads me to one conclusion i have
the mustache i have the chest monster
it's time to do some redstone but i need
the space for the redstone so what we're
going to do
is go and do a super long
grinding time lapse
getting rid of all of these blocks i
don't know how long this is going to
take but i'm guessing very many hours
and i'm going to run this at the same
time since i'm in the area and i will be
able to collect
plenty of sugarcane at the same time
because eventually this has got to go no
no i'm talking to the audience away with
you
so
let's start this time lapse clear out
the area and lay out where this item
sort is going to be let's go
[Music]
[Applause]
it turns out you can't move mountains in
just one day but we have pushed it back
quite a lot i would say we're about 50
of the way
and by looking at how high this goes
i reckon we could fit quite a lot in
here what i didn't count on
is the terrain that is actually
encroaching on this space
so this is actually going to be
an odd shape because i imagine that that
will also be over there but that's
something that we can deal with in time
but as you can see things are going
pretty well we'll continue working on
this throughout the episodes to come
and hopefully start building more of a
structure but the general plan is in
here to have a large
sort of grand hall here
and then have my item sorter all up in
the middle here because i i think it's
the the thing that i'm going to use the
absolute most in this season and i just
wanted to have it as close as possible
easy to access so i literally just come
in i fly fly through the entrance
straight in and i'm in the great hall
and then i've got got myself all the
items that i need now iskall did send me
a little message
saying that the pesky bird delivery deal
has been accepted
oh
pesky bird is holding on to all those
diamonds oh there's a little sign there
i can't i can't read i can't read it the
tip is not for the bird poop it's for
the mussels it's because you're a strong
bird strong independent bird come on
then pesky bird your job here is done
you've collected the diamonds
we must take these and put them
oh
no
all right i'll see you down there pesky
bird take them to the vault
i don't have a vault it's just going in
my ender chest all right i got six
blocks of diamonds for that and that is
54. wait didn't i ask for wait shouldn't
there be seven blocks of diamonds did i
miss one there we go seven blocks of
diamonds so i got a three diamond tip
not bad at all that is a basically a
stack of diamonds and who is that boom
that is that is a decent amount of
diamonds there okay so another thing is
i got a few messages saying can i stock
dirt
on the barge because they would buy a
lot of it now obviously because i've
been terraining a lot well i say terrain
i have been completely removing the
world i have a lot of spare blocks in
this chest monster that is getting
really really bad so i'm gonna take all
of these over to the barge and add them
in for sale my base is just gonna be
covered in pesky birds by the end of the
season all right let's go and deliver
this to the barge
and hopefully
get even more diamonds you know we're
we're pretty prosperous this i forgot
about the mustache
we're being pretty prosperous this
season so far
last season i was pretty poor most of
the time oh oh yeah the button what's
going on with the button is someone i
think someone's camping it x is uh is
waiting i think oh it's on blue and it's
got a long way to go before it's orange
so yeah i mean good luck with that and
there's also a
giant tree things are getting things are
getting a bit weird
here we are on the barge
gonna have to upgrade this again soon
sales of sander down sales of gravel are
down and we made some sales on the name
tag that's awesome all right let's uh
let's pop these here shall we so corster
is actually going to be a bit of an odd
one i i didn't want to do one diamond
for one and a half stacks because that's
a very inefficient way of storing it so
i've done two diamonds for three stacks
that's one and a half diamonds and dirt
will be one block one diamond for three
stacks i have to be really careful not
to sell all of my dirt because it
actually is very very useful for
terraining and stuff there we go
the barge is starting to get more and
more full when all of these platforms
are filled up we're going to upgrade the
barge once more now since we're here
it's time we talked about a little idea
that i've had and it's to do
with this i've been saying a very long
time
that something needs to be done
about this this very large
very
tempting
pile of diamonds now i personally feel i
forgot about the mustache again i
personally feel that these diamonds need
someone to be in charge of them and we
are going to do something about that in
the next episode yes i'm afraid we have
run out of time for today's episode but
new and exciting things will be coming
your way in the next episode of
hermitcraft so i will see you then thank
you very much for watching and good
bye